Wilfrid Swancourt Bronson Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Wilfrid Swancourt Bronson Archives
1925-1930
YPMAR.000051
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
50
Archies of Wilfrid S. Bronson.
Bronson, Wilfrid Swancourt
Biographical Sketch
Artist for Harry Payne Bingham. Accompanied marine expeditions as staff artics for the Bingham Oceanographic Collection.
Description of the Material
Watercolors of mostly fish and some marine invertebrates.
Paintings; Sketches; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Sketches and Paintings, Series I
  - Oil Paintings., 000055
    - Oil painting, 15.5 x 19.5" (39 x 49.5 cm), 1926, Eastern Pacific. 3 Roosterfish, Nematistius pectoralis; 2 Sharks; few Yellowjacks, Gnathanodon speciosus., 000037
    - Oil painting, 23.75 x 32.25" (60.5 x 83 cm), 1927. 2 Barberfish, Heniochus nigrirostris; 1 Yellowtail surgeonfish, Prionurus punctatus; 1 Rock croaker, Paraques viola; 1 Finespotted jawfish, Opistognathus punctatus., 000038
  - Sketches., 000053
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Mutton hamlet, Epinephelus (Alphestes) afer; Panamic soldierfish, Myripristis leiognathos., 000001
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Spotted sand bass, Paralabrax maculatofasciatus; Sargassum blenny, Exerpes asper., 000002
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Barred serrano, Serranus fasciatus., 000003
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Leopard shark, Triakis semifasciata., 000004
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Mutton hamlet, Epinephelus (Alphestes) afer., 000005
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Gulf opaleye, Girella simplicidens., 000006
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Flapscale blenny, Paraclinus sini; Slow goby, Aruma histrio., 000007
    - Watercolor sketch, 8.5 x 11" (21 x 28 cm). Cortez rainbow wrasse, Thalassoma lucasanum., 000008
  - Watercolor Paintings., 000054
    - Watercolor painting, 10 x 14" (25 x 35.5 cm). Green razorfish, Hemipteronotus splendens. BOC 267 and 396., 000009
    - Watercolor painting, 10 x 14" (25 x 35.5 cm). Dwarf wrasses, Doratonotus megalepis. BOC 260, 261, 293, 262, 263, 264; Green razorfish, Hemipteronotus splendens. BOC 268, 269, 270, 271, 272, 273., 000010
    - Watercolor painting, 10.5 x 15" (27 x 38 cm). Royal basslet, Lipogramma regia. BOC 526 (illus. of Bingham type specimen)., 000011
    - Watercolor painting, 14.75 x 10.5" (37.5 x 26.5 cm). Comb grouper, Mycteroperca rubra?; Neon gobies, Gobiosoma oceanops. BOC 371, 372., 000012
    - Watercolor painting, 9 x 14" (22.5 x 35 cm). 3 Yellowhead wrasse, juvenile, Halichoeres garnoti?; 1 Slippery dick, Halichoeres bivittatus. BOC 252., 000013
    - Watercolor painting, 9 x 14" (22.5 x 35 cm). Blackear wrasses, Halichoeres poeyi (H. kirshii). BOC 256, 257, 258, 259, 294., 000014
    - Watercolor painting, 13.25 x 20" (33.5 x 50.5 cm. Spotted goatfish, Upeneus maculatus. BOC 146, 147; Yellow goatfish, Upeneus martinicus. BOC 148, 149., 000015
    - Watercolor painting, 15 x 21.75" (37.5 x 55.5 cm). Gafftopsail pompanos, Trachinotus rhodopus; Scalloped hammerheads, Sphyrna lewini; Flag cabrilla, Epinephelus labriformis., 000016
    - Watercolor painting, 21.5 x 14.25" (55 x 37 cm). Pink frogmouth, Chaunax pictus BOC 525., 000017
    - Watercolor painting, 15 x 21.75" (38 x 55.5 cm). Snake eel, Myrichthys sp.; Giant hawkfish or Clownfish., 000018
    - Watercolor painting, 14.75 x 21.75" (37.5 x 55 cm). Yellowtail snappers, Ocyurus chrysurus; Red snapper, Lutjanus campechanus BOC 552, 553., 000019
    - Watercolor painting, 21.75 x 13" (55.5 x 33 cm). Blue angelfish, Holacanthus bermudensis; 3 Hogfishes, Lachnolaimus maximus., 000020
    - Watercolor painting, 14.25 x 21" (36 x 53.5 cm). Indigo hamlets, Hypoplectrus unicolor; Red-spotted hawkfish, Amblycirrhitus pinos; Black hamlet, Hypoplectrus nigricans; Lantern bass, Serranus sp. ?., 000021
    - Watercolor painting, 14.5 x 21" (37 x 54 cm). Black snappers, Apsilus dentatus. BOC 546, 547; Blackfin snapper, Lutjanus buccanella. BOC 550, 551, 387., 000022
    - Watercolor painting, 14.5 x 21" (37 x 53.5 cm). Spanish hogfish, Bodianus rufus. BOC 249, 389; Puddingwife, Halichoeres radiatus. BOC 390?., 000023
    - Watercolor painting, 13.5 x 18.25" (34.5 x 46.5 cm). 1. Bridle cardinalfish, Amia aurolineatum. BOC 461 type specimen; 2. and 8. Flamefish, Apogon maculatus. BOC 185-191; 3. Barred cardinalfish, Apogon binotatus. BOC 454-457; 4. Unidentifiable; 5., 6., 9. Belted cardinalfish, Amia (now Apogon) townsendi. BOC 460 type specimen; 7. Amia gloverensis. BOC 466 type specimen; 10., 11. Conchfish, Apogonichthys (now Astrapogon) stellatus. BOC 184., 000024
    - Watercolor painting, 19? x 13.25" (49 x 33.5 cm). King angelfish, Holacanthus passer; Mexican hogfish, Bodianus diplotaenia., 000025
    - Watercolor painting, 13? x 19?" (33.5 x 49.25 cm). Possibly ?Rock wrasse, Halichoeres semicinctus; Rock wrasse ?, Halichoeres semicinctus; Unidentified., 000026
    - Watercolor painting, 13.25 x 20?" (33.5 x 52 cm). Deepreef scorpionfish, Scorpaenodes tredecimspinosus; Plumed scorpionfish, Scorpaena grandicornis., 000027
    - Watercolor painting, 29.25 x 21" (74 x 53 cm), 1927. Sheepshead minnows, Cyprinodon variegatus, on bottom; Topminnow, Fundulus, in front of flamingo's leg; 2 Silversides, Atherina laticeps, at top; Flamingo., 000028
    - Watercolor painting, 29.75 x 21.25" (29.75 x 54 cm), 1927. Flying fish, Exocoetidae; Dolphin fish, Coryphaena sp., probably hippurus; Preliminary sketch on reverse., 000029
    - Watercolor painting, 19 x 26" (48 x 66 cm). Rainbow parrotfish, Scarus guacamaia, orig. Sparisoma; Striped parrotfish, Scarus croicensis; Redfin parrotfish, Sparisoma rubripinne., 000030
    - Watercolor painting, 18 x 24" (45.5 x 60.5 cm), 1926. Shovelnose guitarfish, Rhinobatos productus; Wounded wrasse, Halichoeres chierchiae; Rock wrasse, Halichoeres semicinctus ?; Loosetooth parrotfish, Nicholsina denticulata., 000031
    - Watercolor painting, 22 x 24.25" (55.5 x 62 cm), 1926. 4 California sheepshead; 1 Seabass or Grouper., 000032
    - Watercolor painting, 12 x 20.25" (30 x 51.5 cm). 3 Gold-spotted snake eels, Myrichthys oculatus; 2 Sharptail eels, Myrichthys acuminatus., 000033
    - Watercolor painting, 14.5 x 21" (37 x 53.5 cm). Reef squirrelfish, Sargocentron coruscus; Longjaw squirrelfish, Neoniphon marianus; Longspine squirrelfish, Holocentrus rufus., 000034
    - Watercolor painting, 14.75 x 21.5" (37.5 x 54.5 cm). Queen angelfish, Holacanthus ciliaris (above); Rock beauty, Holacanthus tricolor (below)., 000035
    - Watercolor painting, 14.25 x 21" (36 x 54 cm), Caribbean. French angelfish, juvenile, Pomacanthus paru; Beaugregory, juvenile, Stegastes leucostictus; Dusky damselfish, juvenile, Stegastes dorsopunicans; Blue angelfish, juvenile, Holacanthus bermudensis; Rock beauty, juvenile, Holacanthus tricolor., 000036
    - Watercolor painting, 14.25 x 21.5" (37 x 54.5 cm), 1925. 2 species of Grouper., 000039
    - Watercolor painting, 21.25 x 29" (54 x 74 cm), 1928, "Running Before the Seine," Perlas Islands. 6 Filefish (green); 1 Wrasse (pink); 3 Cowfish (spotted); 3 Puffers (orange); school of Needlefish in net., 000040
    - Watercolor painting, 11.75 x 20.25" (29.5 x 51.5 cm). School of Sardine-like fish; Shrimp., 000041
    - Watercolor painting, 12 x 21.5" (31 x 55.5 cm). 2 Oyster toadfish., 000042
    - Watercolor painting, 21 x 14" (53.5 x 35.5 cm), 1928, Fish and buoy. 5 Goatfish; 3 Surgeonfish; 1 Flyingfish (+ 2 faint); 1 Needlefish (near net); 1 Cornetfish; Squid, Jellyfish., 000043
    - Watercolor painting, 21.25 x 14.75" (54 x 37.5 cm)., 000044
    - Fanciful watercolor painting, 6.75 x 8.25" ( 17 x 21 cm), 1927. "Sword"-fish and "Cutlass"-fish., 000045
    - Fanciful watercolor painting, 6.75 x 8.25" ( 17 x 21 cm), 1927. "Sail"-fish., 000046
    - Fanciful watercolor painting, 6.75 x 8.25" ( 17 x 21 cm), 1927. "Butterfly"-fish., 000047
    - Fanciful watercolor painting, 6.75 x 8.25" ( 17 x 21 cm), 1927. "Angel"-fish., 000048
    - Watercolor painting, 28 x 17.25" (71 x 43.5 cm), 1928. 8 Anglerfish; school of Flashlightfish?; 4 Catsharks (red); Krill (red)., 000049
    - Watercolor painting, 29? x 21" (74.5 x 53 cm), 1927. 1 Puffer; 5 Grunts; 1 Squirrelfish (orange); Great Blue Heron., 000050